如果你是太空叉真正的粉丝，这类画面你们一定是见得多了
If you’re a SpaceX fan, you will be familiar with classic shots like this
对于太空飞行来说
When it comes to spaceflight
火箭的主人通常会记录发射的方方面面
rocket companies usually go above and beyond to document every aspect of their launches
在阿波罗的年代，电视台详细地转播了阿波罗11号任务全程
Back in the Apollo days, TV stations covered the entire length of the Apollo 11 mission in great detail
当时全球约有36亿人
尼尔·阿姆斯特朗登上月球的时候，全球有六亿人在看直播
reaching a viewership of 600 million people around the world when Neil Armstrong walked on the moon
“这是人类的一小步……”
"That's one small step for man…"
而最近的重型猎鹰首飞，也有超过一百万人在某个不存在的视频网站上观看直播
The recent Falcon Heavy launch had over 1 million people watching live on YouTube alone
多亏了播出团队，让我们能看到一枚火箭如此壮丽的旅行
Thanks to the broadcast teams, we are able to watch these rockets go on their incredible journeys
而关于一枚火箭，它背后的旅行又是怎样的呢？
But what about the rocket journeys we don’t get to see?
这个视频里，我们将来了解一枚猎鹰九号火箭上发射架前，是如何艰难横穿美国的
In this video, we are going to look at the challenging cross-country journey
the Falcon 9 has to go through in order to reach the launch pad
我们还将了解具体使用的运输方法
We’re also going to talk about the transportation methods that are used
与过去曾使用过的备用方法
and the alternative methods that were used in the past
太空叉在加利福尼亚州的霍索恩生产猎鹰九号火箭
SpaceX manufactures the Falcon 9 rocket at their facility in Hawthorne California
虽然他们的发射主要在佛州的卡纳维拉尔角
although the majority of their rockets launch from Cape Canaveral, Florida
这使得火箭必须跋涉2500英里（4000公里）才能到达发射台
This means they have to go through a two and a half thousand mile journey just to get to the launch site
为了去卡角
In order to get to Cape Canaveral
猎鹰九号被分成几部分，装在大型半挂车上
the Falcon 9 travels in different parts on the back of a huge semi-truck
但在这之前，每一台新的梅林发动机都要送到德克萨斯州的麦格雷戈进行测试
But even before that, every new Merlin engine is transported to their testing facility in McGregor, Texas
发动机将在那里进行一次全程静态点火测试
where it’s put through a full static fire test
之后每台发动机再运回霍索恩，安装在猎鹰九号一级上
Each engine is then transported back to Hawthorne to be attached to the Falcon 9’s first stage
然后，巨大的一级火箭沿陆路运送到卡角
Then, the enormous first stage makes its long journey by road to Cape Canaveral
通常会在麦格雷戈再卸货，作为一个单元进行再更多的静态点火测试
often stopping off in McGregor to perform more static fire tests as a whole unit
二级火箭、整流罩、四个着陆架也都是用卡车单独运到卡角的
The 2nd stage, fairings and each of the 4 landing legs are all transported to the Cape separately by truck
太空叉最主要的物流公司，比如“EZE”，“Beyel Brother”
SpaceX typically contracts private hauling companies like EZE Trucking and Beyel Brothers
会使用44轮的定制拖车来运输猎鹰九号火箭
to transport their Falcon 9 rockets using custom built cradles fitted to a 44 wheeled trailer
猎鹰九号的各部件会蒙上黑布，防止在这四千公里的旅途中受到任何持续性的损伤
The Falcon 9 parts are wrapped in a black fabric which protects them from any damage
that could be sustained during the two and a half thousand mile drive
当它们到达卡角、交还给太空叉之前，会拆封验收
Once they reach the Cape, the Falcon 9 is unwrapped and checked before being handed over to SpaceX
之后太空叉用运输车把火箭运到它们最近刚从NASA那买的组装大楼里
who then transport the rocket to the assembly building on a vehicle they recently bought from NASA
这运输车曾经把航天飞机运送到组装航天飞机和助推器的大楼
This transporter was used to haul the Space Shuttle to the assembly building where it was attached to its boosters
等猎鹰九号在厂房组装好，工人们会把它水平运到发射台
Once the Falcon 9 is assembled in its hangar, the transporter-erector moves it out to the launch pad horizontally
然后竖起到最终位置，准备发射
and then raises it into its final position, ready for launch
与多数火箭不同的是，猎鹰九号火箭的旅途在发射后并没有结束
Unlike most rockets, the Falcon 9’s journey isn’t over after it places it’s payload into orbit
因为太空叉还要回收火箭，所以之后还有运输任务
Since SpaceX intend to re-use their rockets, more transportation is needed
当猎鹰九号降落在大西洋上的无人拖船后
When the Falcon 9 lands on the autonomous drone ship placed in the Atlantic Ocean
两艘回收船“去探索”、“去搜寻”会载着船员把无人船和火箭拖回卡角的港口
recovery vessels Go Quest and Go Searcher will typically be on standby with crew to secure the Falcon 9
to the drone ship and tow it back to the port at Cape Canaveral
目前为止，太空叉只回收过一级火箭
So far, SpaceX has only been recovering the first stage of their rockets
尽然这是猎鹰九号最大、最贵的部分
and although this is the largest and most expensive part of the Falcon 9
但太空叉的长远目标是让火箭完全可回收
SpaceX’s long term aim is to make rockets FULLY reusable
太空叉在设计猎鹰九号的时候，箭体直径被限制在3.7米
When SpaceX were designing the Falcon 9, the diameter of the rocket was limited to 3.7m
使得对于去往佛罗里达的每一座桥，火箭都可以顺利通过
so that the rocket would fit under every bridge and overpass
it would come across on its journey from California to Florida
于是问题来了，为啥要走陆路？
This begs the question, why transport rockets by road?
过去的时候，有很多运输大火箭部件的方法
In the past, there have been many different methods for transporting large rocket parts
在六七十年代，NASA走海路运输土星五号巨大的一级部分到佛罗里达
Back in the 60’s and 70’s, NASA used a sea transport system to transport the massive Saturn V first stage to Florida
火箭十天内顺着田纳西河从阿拉巴马州亨茨维尔到密西西比，跋涉两千英里（3200公里）
This involved a 10 day, 2000 mile journey from Huntsville to Mississippi on the Tennessee River
然后顺着密西西比河一路南下绕回肯尼迪角，在那组装土星五号火箭
and then all the way down the Mississippi River and round the South coast of Florida
然后顺着密西西比河一路南下绕回肯尼迪角，在那组装、发射土星五号火箭
to Cape Kennedy where the Saturn V was assembled and launched
而二级火箭是在加州制造的，所以要乘驳船
Since the second stage was manufactured in California, it had to be transported by barge
一路南下到巴拿马运河，再北上回佛州
through the Panama canal and back up to Florida
空运只是土星五号三级运输的备选方案，通常三级是和二级一起运输的
那为什么还要有空运的方法呢？请看av14026384（视频说明里也有链接）
而对于三级部分及其设备单元，NASA使用了货机
NASA used cargo planes to transport the 3rd stage and the instrument unit to Cape Kennedy
三级直径只有6.5米，可以刚好塞进改装后的波音377PG——“怀孕的古比鱼”
Being only 6.5m in diameter, they were able to squeeze into a cargo aircraft aptly named “Guppy”
这造型就是为这活而专门改装的
specifically designed for loads like this
尽管海运是运输土星五号的主要方式
Although sea transport was the main method of transporting the Saturn V
但还是有需要陆运的场合
there were times when road transport was needed
显然对于一级和二级来说是非常困难的
This proved to be very challenging for the first and second stages
因为它们的直径达到了十米，是猎鹰九号火箭的整整三倍宽
since they were 10m in diameter, a whole 3 times wider than the Falcon 9
所以对于土星五号来说，巨大的体型让海运成为最现实的运输方式
Sea transit might have been the most practical transport method for the Saturn V simply because it was so big
但对于猎鹰九号来说，海运就显得多此一举了
But for rockets like the Falcon 9, shipping the parts this way is not very practical at all
现在，太空叉一直走陆路运输它们几乎所有的火箭组件
Today, SpaceX keeps it simple by transporting nearly all of their rocket parts on land
不止是因为这个方法很现实
Not only is this method the most practical for SpaceX
还因为相比空运和海运而言，陆运很便宜
but it’s also a lot cheaper than the alternative air and sea methods
所以你们知道了吧，酷炫的发射背后，一枚大火箭还要如此“跋山涉水”横穿美国
So there you have it, it turns out there is a lot more that goes on behind the scenes
in transporting these incredibly large rocket parts all across the country
如果你们还想知道关于火箭发射背后的事情
If you’d like to know more about what goes on behind the scenes of a rocket launch
YouTuber名叫Primal Space
上一个视频在av21783104（视频说明里也有链接）
可以看看我之前的视频，关于NASA如何拍摄酷炫的镜头的
check out my video on how rocket launches are filmed
也欢迎大家在评论区讨论
If you have any questions be sure to leave them in the comments below
最后记得关注点赞投币收藏分享一波哦，字幕翻译给虫
and make sure you’re subscribed so you can join the discussion as we continue to learn more about all things space
感谢观看，下期视频见
Thank you very much for watching and I’ll see you in the next video